Peter Kappus

+44 (0) 203 468 4224 hello@peterkappus.com http://kapp.us/cv

Profile

A data-savvy, highly technical digital strategist with a passion for service delivery, organisational transformation, and problem-solving spanning nearly twenty years of experience across a diverse range of industries including government, banking/financial services, media/publishing, and bio-tech.

A natural servant-leader, I specialise in building succssful agile organisations, embeddeing best practice, and creating a strong culture of continuous improvement. I create strong internal communities of practice and nurture lasting positive change while rapidly understanding and delivering to the broader organisational context and strategy.

I combine deep, hands-on technical expertise with excellent communication and leadership skills to influence and engage participants from individual contributors to senior stakeholders bringing about steady, measurable, constant improvement in complex, highly political environments.

Skills

Delivery Management

Strategic cloud hosting

Cloud infrastructure (AWS)

Roadmapping & reporting

Digital service design

Scrum & kanban (CSM)

Stakeholder management

Workshopping / facilitation

Systems thinking, cynefin

Process design / modeling

Behaviour Driven Dev (BDD)

Continuous delivery

Basic Linux DevOps

Source control (git)

GDS Service Manual

Team setup & turn-around

Open source software

Product/service management

Agile governance

Agile / Lean coaching

Code as infrastructure

Adaptive risk management

Target operating model (TOM)

Basic accounting / finance

Goal Setting / Strategy

Data analytics

Ruby on Rails / Python / Java

User Centred Design (UX)

Legacy IT integration

GDS Service Assessment

Experience

Agile PMO | Benefits Realisation Manager

Government Digital Service (Cabinet Office, UK Government)

Nov 2016 - April 2017

Part of the programme management office (PMO) for the Common Technology Services programme which is rolling out common technology solutions and stronger commercial arrangements across government.

- Enabled delivery teams to use agile methodologies to deliver benefits via rapid, continuous iteration with increased transparency
- Developed a robust, flexible and simple processes to roadmap and realise £1.5bn+ in cashable benefits
- Built contract (analysis/management solution)[https://github.com/peterkappus/gds-infoshare] in Ruby on Rails
- Built bespoke online tracking tools and supporting economic models
- · Enabled real-time decision-making for stakeholders and contributors
- · Clearly aligned strategy and delivery teams via tangible benefits
- Dramatically streamlined internal planning/reporting process

Tools & Techniques: Google Sheets w/ scripting, Ruby on Rails, Google Forms, Lean/Agile cost/benefit modelling, Salesforce, etc.

Portfolio Delivery Manager

Government Digital Service (Cabinet Office, UK Government)

Jun 2015 - Nov 2016

Through close engagement with finance, people, and delivery teams combined with strong technical ability I added significant operational agility to the business; enabling senior leadership to make informed, data-driven decisions around prioritisation, investment diversity, delivery, risk, financial performance, headcount and benefits realisation to effectively manage a £500m complex change portfolio (£150m+ in 16/17) driving digital transformation across the UK government and benefiting millions of citizens.

- Replaced complex, inflexible vendor ERP solution with bespoke BI platform
- Saved £100k+ while improving accuracy, engagement, and user satisfaction
- · Reduced reporting cycles from quarterly to monthly
- Trained Del Ops team on tools, concepts, and techniques to ensure lasting change
- Streamlined business planning to make it light-weight, continuous, and real-time
- Introduced impact-mapping and Objectives and Key Results (OKRs)
- Created bespoke OKR tracking tool (https://github.com/peterkappus/panoflex) using Ruby on Rails

Technologies: Google sheets w/ heavy scripting, Google Forms, Ruby on Rails, Hyperion, Anaplan, and others.

Programme Delivery Manager | Agile Coach

Government Digital Service (Cabinet Office, HM Government)

Nov 2014 - Jun 2015

Responsible for delivering the Digital Marketplace (https://www.digitalmarketplace.service.gov.uk/), a revolutionary programme (comprising an online platform, legal & commercial frameworks, and customer support) transforming how the government buys digital. G-Cloud sales (https://www.gov.uk/performance/g-cloud) alone circa £1.4B as of July 2016.

- Active in daily delivery ceremonies (stand-ups, planning, retrospectives, etc).
- Coached teams in agile methodologies, business planning and reporting: resource management, roadmapping, benefits realisation, risk mitigation, stakeholder management

- Oversaw a ~£3M annual budget for a 30+ person cross-functional team (spanning product design, user research, technology, procurement, engagement, support, legal, and analytics)
- Active participant in the Agile delivery community at GDS providing coaching, training, and mentoring across GDS

Technology: Pivotal Tracker, Java (Grails), Python (Flask), Jenkins, SQL Alchemy, git, Postgres, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, continuous integration (CI) with Jenkins, infrastructure automation with Ansible, AWS Relational Data Store (RDS). All code open sourced via github (https://github.com/alphagov/? utf8=%E2%9C%93&query=digitalmarketplace).

Delivery Manager | Agile Transformation Coach

Pearson PLC

Jul 2013 - Nov 2014

Successfully delivered two critical, at-risk programmes by transitioning from a dysfunctional waterfal to a high-functioning, lean/agile practice using Scrum, Lean, kanban, retrospectives, rapid prototyping, user testing, etc.

- Turned stakeholders from sceptics to partners by improving efficacy, quality and time to market while reducing cost
- Demonstrated high customer satisfaction with real data
- Transitioned from legacy ITIL to modern DevOps culture
- Introduced BDD using Capybara, Cucumber, phantomJS, and more
- Delieverd complete redesign, rebuild, and platform migration of the Pearson Qualifications
 (https://qualifications.pearson.com) website (a £300M+ annual business with 60K+ pages and documents)
 from SharePoint to Adobe Experience Manager (CQ)
- Embedded lasting change: improved ways of working continue to deliver benefits today
- Delivered a real-time analytics platform using Big Data and Machine Learning to predict subscription renewal rates and identify at-risk clients
- Mentored senior stakeholders in lean/agile methodologies supporting wider digital transformation of the world's largest publishing company.

Technologies: Single Sign on, Jira, Adobe CQ (Java), Solr, AngularJS, Apache, Jenkins, Cucumber (Ruby, Capybara, Poltergeist, PhantomJS), MySQL, CouchDB, MongoDB, Python/Flask, SOA/RESTful APIs

Delivery Manager | Agile Coach

American Express (via ustwo™)

Nov 2012 - May 2013

Managed front-end/UX delivery and coached technical and leadership teams at a Fortune 100 credit-card company to deliver a multi-million dollar customer loyalty programme targeting over 1m households at launch.

- On-shore, near-shore, and off-shore teams in London, Boston, New York, Bangalore, Munich and Phoenix
- · Facilitated agile ceremonies including sprint planning, stand-ups, show & tells, and retrospectives
- Resulted in timely, high-quality delivery across multiple platforms

Tech stack included JIRA, Java EE, SDLC, SOA, Scrum, Agile, User Experience (UX), iOS, Android, Responsive Web

Product Owner | Data Scientist

Gray Metrics

Apr 2012 - Nov 2012

Applied agile/lean principles and engineering capability enabling a **big data start-up** to conceive and deliver a first-gen social media data mining and trend analysis platform for the automobile industry. Included market strategy, product ownership, engineering, and business development. **AWS (EC2), MongoDB, Ruby on Rails, Jetty, D3.js, and R**

Scrum Master | Agile Coach

JAM @ Engine People Limited

Aug 2011 - Mar 2012

Managed delivery of a real-time social media management and analytics platform to web and mobile channels. Servant leader to a team of engineers, designers, and business owners between the UK & South America. Provided individualised coaching to embed lasting agile transformation. JIRA, SOA, RESTful APIs, PHP, MySQL, Apache, Tomcat, Java EE, GNIP, Watir, jQuery, Automated Testing, iOS, Android, Windows Phone.

Delivery Manager

Credit Suisse (via ustwo™)

Aug 2010 - Aug 2011

Managed front-end design and delivery of an award-winning **Fixed Income (forex)** Single Dealer Platform (SDP) for a **global Tier 1 investment bank** including support for **cash**, **options**, **and algorithmic trading**. Worked with multiple stake-holders across various lines of business including client services, product management, and information technology. Introduced bespoke agile design process within the bank's legacy SDLC. Employed **JIRA**, **Confluence**, **OmniPlan**, **OmniFocus**, **Axure**, **Nirvana**, **Java EE**, **XAML**, **Silverlight**, **HTML**, **CSS**, and **Javascript**.

Senior Project Management Consultant

Cellnovo (via ustwo™)

Dec 2009 - Aug 2010

Managed delivery of a ground-breaking wireless web-enabled insulin pump with touch-screen UI (requiring CE Mark and EN-60601-1 compliant embedded software). Reported directly to Chief Executive Officer and liaised with in-house and vendor teams in London, Winchester, Poland, and Wales. Applied agile methods to create a robust engineering, UX, and defect management processes prior to arrival of VP of engineering. Routinely met with investors and board members. OmniGraffle, SpiraTeam, OmniPlan, C++, ANT-RF, GSM, ActionScript, WinCE, HaXe.

Owner, Director of Technology

Design Commission, Inc.

Sep 2006 - Aug 2009

Managing Director/Owner of a **full-service digital design and development agency**. Increased revenue 350% and grew headcount from 2 to 12 people. Responsibile for corporate strategy, account management, business development, forecasting and budgeting, employee development and retention, project management, technical delivery, user experience, information architecture and vendor management. **Ruby on Rails, PHP, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, WordPress, ActionScript, Flash, Agile/Scrum, BaseCamp, Lighthouse, Rally, OmniFocus, OmniGraffle, GTD, Harvest, QuickBooks, MS Office, Google Analytics, Omniture, TextMate, MySQL.**

Founder / CTO

Boom Bucket Mobile

Founder and CTO of a **mobile content** start-up. Built **digital asset management** platform for ingesting, cataloging, showcasing, distributing, and reporting on thousands of mobile wallpapers and ringtones. Also responsible for **business development and marketing** including the company's 2006 launch at *Mobile World Congress* in Barcelona Spain. **HTML, ActionScript, JavaScript, PHP, and MySQL.**

Senior Producer

Corbis, Inc.

Feb 2000 - May 2006

Managed technical delivery of new Corbis Motion e-licensing platform and multiple online marketing campaigns. Designed, built, and deployed a Perl-based **content management and localisation product** enabling localised delivery of an E-Commerce platform with \$13M annual turn-over to five markets in under two weeks. **Flash, ActionScript, ASP.NET, SQLServer, Perl, HTML, and JavaScript.**

Additional experience available upon request

Education

University of Colorado at Boulder, USA

Bachelor of Arts in Environmental Design (Architecture) - 3.75 GPA

Additional coursework in computer science

Rhode Island School of Design, USA

European Honors Program (EHP) Art History/Architecture studio — 4.0 GPA

Additional courses, certifications, and conferences available upon request

Miscellany

Dual-national (US & UK). Musician, composer, abstract artist, and conversational French-speaker. Self-appointed world diplomat. Able to leap tall buildings in a single bound.

Learn more at http://www.peterkappus.com